socrative.com 2019-07-28

# Privacy Policy - Socrative

Last Updated: December 17, 2018

Showbie Inc. (“Showbie”) values your privacy. In this Socrative.com Privacy Policy (“Privacy Policy”), we describe how we collect, use, and disclose information that we obtain about visitors to our website www.socrative.com (the “Site”), users of our mobile applications (the “Apps”), and users of the services available through our Site and Apps (collectively, the “Services”). It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access, update and exercise other rights in respect of your personal information. The Site, Apps and Services are owned and operated by Showbie Inc., #403, 10113 104 Street NW, Edmonton, Alberta, Canada T5J 1A1.

By submitting Personal Data (as defined below) through our Site, Apps or Services, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, and you expressly consent to the collection, use and disclosure of your Personal Data in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

IF YOU ARE A PARENT OR TEACHER OF A CHILD UNDER THIRTEEN YEARS OLD, PLEASE [CLICK HERE](https://socrative.com/privacy.html#coppa) TO REVIEW OUR COPPA PRIVACY POLICY, WHICH CONTAINS IMPORTANT INFORMATION FOR PARENTS ABOUT HOW WE COLLECT, USE, AND DISCLOSE THE PERSONAL INFORMATION WE COLLECT FROM CHILDREN UNDER THIRTEEN YEARS OLD.

#### Summary of Key Points

  * **We collect**  Personal Data from Teachers and Parents when a Teacher or Parent accesses and takes actions on our Site, Apps or Services, such as when a Teacher or Parent creates an Account. We also collect Personal Data from Teachers when a Teacher creates and posts content to his or her Profile and/or Newsfeed and interacts with other users, including with Students.
  *  **We collect**  Personal Data about Students that is provided to us by Teachers or Schools, such as their names, student assessment responses and other evidence of learning. If a Teacher creates an Account on behalf of the Student, we collect limited Personal Data about the Student from the Teacher to establish the Account.
  *  **We use**  the Personal Data we collect to provide Teachers, Parents and Students with the Services. For instance, we use Personal Data to enable Teachers to edit and manage their Accounts, Profiles and/or Newsfeeds, to enable Teachers to load and share content including Resource Pins and Educational Materials (both as defined below), and to enable Teachers to connect with their Students, Parents, and other Teachers. We also use Personal Data to enable Teachers, Parents and Students to access and view assessment responses, evidence of learning, Resources Pins, Educational Materials, as well as all other features of the Services.
  *  **We share**  Teacher Personal Data with other Teachers through a Teacher’s Profile and/or Newsfeed, depending on the Newsfeed privacy settings. We share Teacher Personal Data with Students and Parents but limited to only the Teacher’s name and School.
  *  **We share**  Student Personal Data only in limited ways. We share Student Personal Data only with that Student’s Teacher(s) and Parent(s) and as expressly described in this Privacy Policy and our COPPA Privacy Policy.
  *  **We also share**  Personal Data of all users of the Site, Apps, and Services with third parties but only for the express purpose of helping us to provide the Services.
  *  **We use cookies and other tracking and analytic technologies**  on our Site and in our Services to track the use of our Site and Services and to enhance the functionality of our Site and Services.
  *  **We do not host third party advertisements**  on our Site, Apps or Services. We do not provide Personal Data to third parties for their own marketing purposes.
  * For more information about  **your choices**  regarding your Personal Data, including how to access or modify your Personal Data, please see the section title “Your Choices Regarding Your Data.”

#### Contact Us

If you have questions about the privacy aspects of our Services or would like to make a complaint, please contact us at:

Showbie  
#403, 10113 104 Street NW  
Edmonton, AB T5J 1A1 Canada  

#### What Information Do We Collect About You?

We may collect Personal Data from end users affiliated with a particular school or other educational institution or organization (“School”) who are teachers or administrators (“Teachers”), students, which may include children under the age of 13 (“Students”), and parents or legal guardians of Students (“Parents”) as each uses our Site, Apps and Services (any individual end user in one of these groups or all three collectively may be referred to as “you”). “Personal Data” means personal information about an identifiable individual and any information which can be used to identify an individual as well as any other non-public information about you that is associated with or linked to any of the foregoing data. We may also collect Anonymous Data. “Anonymous Data” means data that is not associated with or linked to your Personal Data; Anonymous Data does not, by itself, permit the identification of individual persons. To the extent that Anonymous Data is linked with your Personal Data, we will treat it as Personal Data.

We collect Personal Data and Anonymous Data that Teachers, Parents and Students provide to us directly. We may also collect Personal Data or Anonymous Data automatically, through technologies used on the Site, in the Apps and in the Services, as described below.

#### Information we collect directly from you

**Information we collect from Teachers and Parents:**

  * Certain areas and features of our Site, Apps, and Services may require you to register for an account through which you can log in to access the Services (“Account”). If you register for an Account as a Teacher or Parent, we will collect your (1) email address and/or username and (2) a password.
  * We may collect and retain information on your behalf, such as files and messages that you store and/or share using your Account.
  * If you participate in one of our surveys, we may collect additional profile information.
  * If you choose to provide it, we may collect any feedback, testimonials or comments you may provide to us about your use of the Site, Apps or Services.
  * If you contact us via email to provide comments, feedback, or to request support for the Services, we may collect other types of Personal Data, such as your operating system and version, as applicable, your IP address, and other requested information.
  * We may also collect Personal Data at other points in our Site that state that Personal Data is being collected.

 **Information we collect only from Teachers:**

  * We collect your first name and last name, email address, country, state in which you teach, zip code, school name, and school district to create your profile on the Site, Apps and Services (“Profile”). If you choose to provide it, we may also collect additional information for your Profile including, but not limited to, your photograph, job title, the grade that you teach, the subject(s) that you teach, and the address of the School where you teach.
  * If you choose to post messages or other content on the Site, Apps or Services using your Account or Profile, such as through the newsfeed function on your Account (“Newsfeed”), the information contained in your posting will be stored on our servers and will be viewable by all other users unless you choose to make your Newsfeed private through the privacy settings on your Account.
  * If you choose to provide them, any learning assessments, links or references to external educational and learning resources (“Resource Pins”), curriculum maps, student scores or other academic or educational resources or materials (“Educational Materials”) that you choose to upload to your Account.
  * If you make a purchase on our Site or Apps or through our Services, we will collect all information needed to complete the transaction, including but not limited to your e-mail address and password, credit card information, and name on your credit card. For more information about payment processing, please see below.
  * If you choose to provide it, the name or other select Profile information to identify another Teacher whose Newsfeeds you wish to follow and about whom you wish to receive updates and other information on the Site, Apps or Services (“Follow”).

 **Information we collect from Students:**

  * We do not require Students to register for an Account to use the Site, Apps or Service. To log on to the Services, each Student is prompted to enter either a unique and anonymous assessment ID, which will be provided to the Student by a Teacher, or a unique and anonymous student ID generated either by the School or by Socrative.
  * If a Teacher chooses to register a Student for an Account, Socrative will generate a user name and temporary password and provide directly to the Teacher who may then share with the Student. The only information we collect directly from the Student is a permanent password for their Account.
  * We may collect a Student’s name, assessment information, and other information as directed by the Student’s Teacher or School. We limit the information we collect about Students to only that information necessary to provide the Service. We do not use the Student’s Personal Data for our own commercial purposes.
  * We collect Student assessment responses and may archive evidence of learning.

#### Information We Collect Automatically

  * We may automatically collect the following information about your use of our Site, Apps, or Services through our servers and in log files: domain name; browser type and operating system; web pages viewed; links clicked; the length of time spent on our Site or Apps; the length of time our Services are used; the referring URL, or the webpage that led a user to our Site; language information; device name and model; operating system type, name, and version; and activities within our Site and Apps. We use this information to analyze trends, administer the Site, track users’ movements around the Site, gather demographic information about our user base as a whole, and better tailor our Services to our users’ needs. We do not link this automatically-collected data to Personal Data.
  * We may also collect IP address, device identifier or a similar unique identifier from users of our Apps and Site; we only use such identifiers to support the internal operations of our Site and Apps in the same manner as described above.
  * We may also collect non-personal information from your mobile device if you have downloaded our Apps. This information is generally used to help us deliver the most relevant information to you. Examples of information that may be collected and used include how you use the Apps and information about the type of device you use. In addition, in the event our Apps crash on your mobile device, we will receive information about your mobile device model software version and device carrier, which allows us to identify and fix bugs and otherwise improve the performance of our Apps. This information is sent to us as aggregated information and is not traceable to any individual and cannot be used to identify an individual.

#### Information About You That We Collect From Schools

  * If you are a Teacher or Parent, your Student’s School may provide us with your name and email address to facilitate your registration for the Services.
  * If you are a Teacher, your School may provide us with additional Personal Data to assist us in providing the Services to you and your Students.

#### Information About Third Parties You Invite to Use the Site, Apps or Services

If you are a Teacher and you choose to invite another teacher or parent to use our Site, Apps or the Services, we will ask you for that teacher’s or parent’s name and email address. We will automatically send the teacher or parent an invitation email inviting him or her to visit the Site and join the Services. Socrative stores this information for the sole purpose of sending these invitation emails and tracking the success of our referral program. The teacher or parent you invite may contact us at [legal@socrative.com](mailto:legal@socrative.com) to request that we remove this information from our database.

#### Information We Receive from Third Parties

The Services allow you to access Facebook to obtain a profile photograph for your account. Depending on whether you are already signed into Facebook or have an existing account with Facebook, you may be prompted to sign in or register with Facebook. By proceeding, you are allowing the Services to access your information and you are agreeing to the Facebook Terms of Use. Once you register on the Site or Apps and connect with Facebook, you will be able to automatically select a photo from your profile on Facebook.

In some cases, the Services may allow you to set up an Account and/or sign in using your Google Plus ID or your Clever ID. If you choose to use this option, if available, we will receive information for the sole purpose of setting up your Account and/or enabling you to sign in to your existing Account.

#### How We Use Your Information

**General Use**

We use the information that we gather about you for the following purposes:

  * To provide you with our Services, as applicable to Teachers, Students and Parents;
  * To facilitate creation of your Account on our Site or Apps;
  * To identify you as a user in our system;
  * To provide improved administration of our Site, Apps and Services;
  * To send you a welcome email to verify ownership of the email address provided when your Account was created;
  * To send you administrative notifications via email;
  * To respond to inquiries that you send to us, including your customer service requests, and for other customer service purposes; and
  * To provide Students, Parents and Teachers with information and reports about Student performance and use of the Site, Apps, and Services.

If you are a Teacher, we also use the information that we gather about you for the following additional purposes:

  * To tailor the content and information that we may send or display to you, to offer personalized help and instructions, and to otherwise personalize your experiences while using the Site, Apps, or Services;
  * To enable you to create and post content to your Profile through your Account, load and share Resource Pins and other Educational Materials, enable you to Follow other users and to enable you to post and share content on your Newsfeed; and
  * To send you news and newsletters, special offers, and promotions from Socrative, or to otherwise contact you with information we think may be of interest related to Socrative products and services. You are able to change your preferences under your Profile settings if you wish to opt out of these types of emails. We will not send marketing or promotional materials to Student users.

#### Aggregated or Anonymous Data

We may aggregate or anonymize data we collect to create Anonymous Data. Anonymous Data does not identify you individually. We may use this Anonymous Data for our own purposes, such as to better understand how users access and use our Site, Apps, and Services in order to improve our Site, Apps, and Services and respond to user desires and preferences, and for other research and analytical purposes. We also may disclose Anonymous Data to third parties in order to meet these purposes.

#### How We Share Your Information

We do not sell your Personal Data. We will disclose the Personal Data that we collect from you only as described in this Privacy Policy.

We may employ third party companies and individuals to facilitate our Service (“Service Providers”), to provide the Service on our behalf, to perform service-related services or to assist us in analyzing how our service is used. [Here](https://help.socrative.com/privacy-and-security/who-socrative-shares-your-data-with) is a list of service providers Socrative currently uses.

These third parties have access to your Personal Information only to perform these tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose. In cases of onward transfer to third parties of Personal Information received, Showbie is potentially liable.

We may disclose Personal Data as follows:

  * Teacher Data. If you are a Teacher, we will share the Educational Materials, Resource Pins and other information that you load through your Account with the other Teachers, Students and Parents that you have allowed to receive it. We will share any information that you post on your Profile with other Teachers. We will share any information that you post to your Newsfeed based on the privacy settings you have selected.
  * Student Data. We will disclose Personal Data of Students: (1) to each Student’s individual Teacher(s) and their Parent(s); (2) as directed by the Student’s Teacher(s) or school; and (3) as further described in our COPPA Privacy Policy. The Student’s Teacher(s) may share the Student’s scores, academic progress data or other academic information (“Academic Data”) with other Teachers.
  * Third Party Service Providers. We may disclose Personal Data to third-party vendors, service providers, contractors or agents who perform functions on our behalf and/or at the request of a school or district customer in order to: provide you with the Services that we offer you through our Site and Apps; conduct quality assurance testing; facilitate creation of accounts; provide technical support; and/or provide other services to us. Some of these service providers are located in United States. A list of our third-party service providers is available upon request. These third party service providers are required not to use your Personal Data other than to provide the services requested by the Company. We will not disclose Personal Data to third parties for any purposes not described in this Privacy Policy.
  * Business Transfers. If we are acquired by or merged with another company, if substantially all of our assets are transferred to another company, or as part of a bankruptcy proceeding, we may transfer the Personal Data we have collected to the other company. We will notify you via email and/or a prominent notice on our Site of any change in ownership or uses of your Personal Data, as well as any choices you may have regarding your Personal Data.
  * In Response to Legal Process. We may disclose Personal Data in order to comply with applicable law, a judicial proceeding, court order, or other legal process.
  * To Protect Us and Others. We may disclose Personal Data where we believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the safety of any person, violations of our Terms of Service or this Privacy Policy, or as evidence in litigation in which Socrative is involved.
  * No Disclosure to Third Party Companies for Marketing. As stated above, we will not disclose your Personal Data to any third party company for the third party company’s own direct marketing purposes.
  * Disclosure to Other Third Parties Only With Consent. Beyond the disclosures described in this Privacy Policy, Socrative will not disclose your Personal Data to any other third party without your consent to do so.

#### Public Comments

If you make any comments to a Newsfeed, Educational Materials, Resource Pins or other items or forums associated with the Site or Apps that are publicly viewable by the Socrative community, you should be aware that any Personal Data you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for Personal Data that you choose to submit in these blogs and forums.

#### Our Use of Cookies and Other Tracking Mechanisms

**Cookies.**  We use cookies to track information about your use of our Site, Apps, or Services. “Cookies” are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to your computer’s hard drive through your web browser for record-keeping purposes. We may use both session Cookies (which expire once you close your web browser) and persistent Cookies (which stay on your computer until you delete them). Some Cookies allow us to make it easier for you to navigate our Site and Services, while others are used to enable a faster log-in process or to allow us to track your activities but only as those activities relate to your use of our Site and Service.

**Third-Party Analytics.**  We may also use third party analytics tools and technologies, such as Google Analytics, to track and analyze data from our Site, Apps, or Services. Google Analytics uses Cookies to collect information such as how often users visit the Site, what pages they visit, and what other site they used prior to coming to the Site. We use the data collected by such third party analytics tools only to help us administer and improve the quality of our Site, Apps, and Services and to analyze usage. These third parties are not permitted to use the information collected on our behalf, except to help us conduct and improve our business. Google Analytics collects only the IP address assigned to you on the date you visit the Site, rather than your name or other personally identifying information. Although Google Analytics plants a persistent Cookie on your web browser to identify you as a unique user the next time you visit the Site, the Cookie cannot be used by anyone but Google. Google’s ability to use and share information collected by Google Analytics about your visits to the Site is restricted by the Google Analytics Terms of Use and the Google Privacy Policy. For more information on Google’s privacy practices, please [click here](https://www.google.com/intl/en/analytics/learn/privacy.html). For information about how to opt out of Google Analytics, please [click here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

**How We Respond to Do Not Track Signals.**  We do not currently respond to “do not track” signals from web browsers.

#### Teacher Profiles

  * If you are a Teacher, the Personal Data you provide on your Profile, including your profile photo, is made public by default on the Site, Apps and Services and is viewable by other Teachers.
  * By default, messages that you post to your Newsfeed, as well the names of users you are Following and users who are Following you, are public and viewable by other Teachers. However, you have the option to make your Newsfeed private through the privacy settings on your Account. If you choose to make your Newsfeed private, it will be viewable to only those users who are Following you.
  * Once displayed publicly, the information you post in your Profile and Newsfeed can be collected and used by others. We cannot control who reads your Newsfeed, postings or what other users may do with the information that you voluntarily post, so it is very important that you exercise caution with respect to any Personal Data that you include in your posts. Once you have posted information publicly, while you will still be able to edit and delete it on the Site or App, you will not be able to edit or delete such information cached, collected, and stored elsewhere by others (e.g., search engines).

#### Payment Processing

For online payments we use the payment services of PayPal (https://www.paypal.com). We do not process, record or maintain your credit card or bank account information. For more information on how payments are handled, or to understand the data security and privacy afforded such information, please refer to https://www.paypal.com/us/webapps/mpp/security/security-protections.

#### Third-Party Links

Our Site, Apps, and Services may contain links to third-party websites. Any access to and use of such linked websites is not governed by this Privacy Policy, but instead is governed by the privacy policies of those third-party websites. We are not responsible for the information practices of such third-party websites.

#### Security of Your Personal Data

We have implemented a variety of security measures to protect the Personal Data we collect from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction. We protect your login information and the transmission of data using Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology.

You should take steps to protect against unauthorized access to your password, phone, and computer by, among other things, signing off after using a shared computer, choosing a robust password that nobody else knows or can easily guess, and keeping your log-in and password private. We are not responsible for any lost, stolen, or compromised passwords or for any activity on your account via unauthorized password activity.

#### Your Choices Regarding Your Personal Data

You have several choices regarding our use of your information on our Services:

**Accessing and Deleting Your Personal Data**

  * You may request a copy of the Personal Data Socrative has about you.
  * You may edit or delete any of the non-required information from your Personal Data through the profile page in your Account on our Site or Apps.
  * You may request deletion of your Personal Data or your entire Account by us by using [this form](https://showbie.typeform.com/to/y1bMQz) and you may also request that Socrative limit further processing.
  * Please note that copies of information that you have updated, modified or deleted may remain viewable in cached and archived pages of the Site or Apps for a period of time.

 **Marketing Communications**

We may send periodic promotional or informational emails to Teacher users about Socrative services, products, or events. You may opt out of such communications by following the opt-out instructions contained in the e-mail. Please note that it may take up to 10 business days for us to process opt-out requests. If you opt out of receiving emails about recommendations or other information we think may interest you, we may still send you administrative e-mails about your account or any Services you have requested or received from us.

**Disabling Cookies**

Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but if you prefer, you can edit your browser options to block them in the future. The Help portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your computer from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable cookies altogether. Visitors to our Site who disable cookies will be able to browse certain areas of the Site, but some features may not be available to you.

**Applications**

You can stop all collection of information by the Apps by uninstalling the Apps. You may use the standard uninstall processes as may be available as part of your mobile device or via the mobile application marketplace or network.

#### Residents of the European Economic Area

For residents of the European Economic Area, Socrative generally processes Personal Data in order to fulfill contracts we have with our customers and users and to pursue our legitimate business interests listed above. Otherwise, Socrative will obtain consent from a data subject in respect of processing of Personal Data if required by law to do so.

This Privacy Policy does not apply to the practices of companies that we do not own or control. Our customers are responsible for maintaining their own privacy policies governing the collection, use and disclosure of Personal Data and are responsible for ensuring that they have obtained the necessary authorizations and consents for any Personal Data made available to us for use in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

#### Changes to This Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy is current as of the Last Updated Date set forth above. We may update this Privacy Policy from time to time to reflect changes in our information processing practices. If we make any material changes to this Privacy Policy, we will notify you at the email address that we have on file for you in advance of the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

#### COPPA Privacy Policy

Showbie Inc. (“Socrative”) values the privacy of children and of all of its users. This COPPA Privacy Policy (“COPPA Policy”) is designed to comply with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (“COPPA”) and contains important information about how we collect, use, and disclose the personal information we collect from children under thirteen years old who use our website, www.socrative.com (the “Site”), our mobile applications (the “Apps”), and the services available through our Site and Apps (collectively, the “Services”). This COPPA Policy also explains how a parent or guardian (“parent” or “you”) can restrict the collection, use and/or disclosure of your Child’s (as defined below) information and how you can request deletion of your Child’s information.

The Socrative Services are a classroom tool and resource that teacher end users (“Teachers”) can use as part of their classroom activities to identify levels of student understanding around their instruction on a real-time basis. To use the Services, Teachers may collect personal information from their students, including children who are under 13 years old (“Students”). For the purposes of this Policy, “Child” or “Children” means a Student under 13 years old.

When a Teacher uses our Services in the classroom or an educational setting, such as to sign Students up for the Services, or to assign response activities to Students and track their progress, the Teacher is required to provide consent to the collection and use of personal information from and about Children as required under applicable laws, including but not limited to COPPA and Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (“FERPA”). Teachers and the schools or other academic institutions with which the Teachers and the Teachers’ Students are affiliated (“Schools”) are also responsible for providing parents with notice about how personal information from their Child(ren) is collected and used by us.

Children’s personal information will be handled only as described in this COPPA Policy. Any personal information we collect about other users (e.g., Students over 13 years old, Teachers, and parents) will be treated in accordance with the Socrative Privacy Policy (“Privacy Policy”).

#### Who Will Collect Information About Children?

Showbie Inc. operates the Site, Apps, and Services and will collect Children’s personal information as described in this COPPA Policy. We can be contacted at:

Showbie  
#403, 10113 104 Street NW  
Edmonton, AB T5J 1A1 Canada  

#### What Information Do We Collect About Children?

**How Information is Collected.**  We may collect information about Children  **directly**  from Children and/or their Teachers, as well as  **automatically**  through a Child’s use of our Site, Apps, and/or Services. We will not require a Child to disclose more information than is reasonably necessary to use our Services. Further, as explained below, we will not collect a Child’s name, contact information, or other personal information directly unless a Teacher or School requests it. We provide Teachers and Schools with a notice regarding our privacy practices.

**Information We Collect Directly.**  Socrative does not require Children to submit name, contact information, or other personal information to us to register for our Site, Apps or Services. To log on to the Services, Children are prompted to enter either a unique and anonymous assessment ID, which will be provided to the Student by a Teacher, and/or a unique and anonymous student ID generated either by the School or by Socrative.

We may collect a Child’s name and other limited personal information directly from a Child’s Teacher or School. Through our Services, Teachers can create assessments and track their Students’ learning progress. In doing so, Teachers may require the Child’s personal information in order to track and archive evidence of learning. Teachers are responsible for ensuring that their collection and use of personal information from Children complies with applicable laws, including COPPA and FERPA. If you are a parent and you have questions about your Child’s Teacher’s use of our Services and any information collected, you should discuss your questions with your child’s Teacher or School.

A Teacher has the option of creating an account on behalf of their Students which allows those Students to view their learning progress and access learning resources provided by their Teacher. If a Teacher chooses to register a Child for an account, Socrative will generate a user name and temporary password and provide directly to the Teacher who may then share with the Child. The only information we collect directly from the Child is a permanent password for their account.

We collect information about Children’s performance and activities on our Site, Apps, and Services, including the assessments taken, questions answered, and other evidence of learning. This information is made available to Teachers in personally identifiable form; we do not use this information in personally identifiable form for our own commercial purposes. If we analyze or use any activity data for our own commercial purposes, we will de-identify and/or aggregate such information.

Parents can tell us to stop collecting personal information from their Child(ren); however, in such cases the Child(ren) will not be able to use our Services, as they are intended to be controlled by a Teacher. If you direct us to stop collecting and using your Child’s personal information, we must disable his or her use of our Services to ensure that no information is collected via the Teacher’s use of Socrative as a classroom tool.

**Information We Collect Automatically.**  We may automatically collect the following information about a Child’s use of our Site, Apps, or Services through our servers and in log files: domain name; browser type and operating system; web pages viewed; links clicked; the length of time spent on our Site or Apps; the length of time our Services are used; the referring URL, or the webpage that led a user to our Site; language information; device name and model; operating system type, name, and version; and activities within our Site and Apps. We use this information to analyze trends, administer the Site, track users’ movements around the Site, gather demographic information about our user base as a whole, and better tailor our Services to our users’ needs. Except as noted in this COPPA Policy, we do not link this automatically-collected data to a Child’s personal information.

We may also collect IP address, device identifier or a similar unique identifier from users of our Apps and Site; we only use such identifiers to support the internal operations of our Site and Apps in the same manner as described above.

We may also collect information from any mobile devices that a Child uses if the Child has downloaded one or more of our Apps to the device. This information is generally used to help us deliver the most relevant information to the Child. Examples of information that may be collected and used include how the Child uses the App(s) and information about the type of device the Child is using. In addition, in the event our App(s) crash on a mobile device, we will receive information about the mobile device model software version and device carrier, which allows us to identify and fix bugs and otherwise improve the performance of our App(s). This information is sent to us as aggregated information and is not traceable to any individual and cannot be used to identify an individual.

#### How We Use Children’s Information

We use the personal information that we collect from Children for the following general purposes:

  * To provide our Services;
  * To respond to customer service and technical support issues and requests;
  * To identify the Child as a user in our system;
  * To provide improved administration of our Site, App and Services; and
  * To tailor the content and information that we may display to Children, to offer personalized help and instructions, and to otherwise personalize a Child’s experiences while using the Site, Apps, or Services.

 **As Requested by Teachers.**  When a Teacher or School provides a Child’s name and other personal information, we use that personal information for the following additional purposes:

  * To provide Children and Teachers with information and reports about a Child’s performance and use of the Site, Apps, and Services;
  * If requested, to facilitate creation of a Child’s account;
  * We do not use or disclose this personal information for our own commercial purposes.

 **Unique Identifiers.**  As noted, with the exception of unique identifiers (e.g., IP address and device identifiers), our Site, Apps, and Services will not collect personal information from Children. We only collect and use unique identifiers as necessary to operate our Site, Apps, and Services, including to maintain or analyze their functioning; perform network communications; authenticate users or personalize content; and protect the security or integrity of users and our Site, App, and Services. We never use unique identifiers to track users across third party apps or websites.

**Aggregate or De-identified Information.**  We may use aggregate or de-identified information about Children for research, analysis, and similar purposes. When we do so, we strip out names, email, contact information, and other personal identifiers. For example, we may use aggregate or de-identified information for one or more of the following purposes, among other purposes:

  * To better understand how users access and use our Site, Apps, and Services;
  * To improve our Site, Apps, and Services and respond to user desires and preferences; and
  * For other research and analytical purposes.

#### How We Share Children’s Information

We do not sell Children’s personal information, and a Child may not make his or her personal information public through our services (though Teachers may choose to share a Child’s information and responses with the Child’s classmates or with other Teachers). We will disclose the personal information that we collect from Children only as described in this COPPA Policy. We may disclose Children’s personal information as follows:

  * **Parents, Teachers and Classmates.**  We will disclose Children’s personal information: (1) to each Child’s individual Teacher(s) and parent(s); and (2) as directed by the Child’s Teacher(s) or School. The Child’s Teacher(s) may share the Child’s scores, academic progress data or other academic information (“Academic Data”) with other Children in the Child’s class or school and with other Teachers. Parents may request information about the information we have collected from their Child(ren) by contacting us at [legal@socrative.com](mailto:legal@socrative.com).
  *  **Third Party Service Providers.**  We may disclose a Child’s personal information to third-party vendors, service providers, contractors or agents who perform functions on our behalf and/or at the request of a school or district customer in order to: provide the Child and the Child’s Teacher with the Services that we offer through our Site and Apps; conduct quality assurance testing; facilitate creation of accounts; provide technical support; and/or provide other services to us. These third party service providers are required not to use personal information other than to provide the services requested by Company. We will not disclose Personal Data to third parties for any purposes not described in this COPPA Policy.
  *  **Business Transfers.**  If we are acquired by or merged with another company, if substantially all of our assets are transferred to another company, or as part of a bankruptcy proceeding, we may transfer the personal information we have collected from Children to the other company. We will notify all users via email and/or a prominent notice on our Site of any change in ownership or uses of the personal information we have collected, as well as any choices users may have regarding their personal information.
  *  **In Response to Legal Process.**  We may disclose personal information that we have collected from Children in order to comply with applicable law, a judicial proceeding, court order, or other legal process.
  *  **To Protect Us and Others.**  We may disclose personal information that we have collected from Children where we believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the safety of any person, violations of our Terms of Service, our Socrative Privacy Policy or this COPPA Policy, or as evidence in litigation in which Socrative is involved.
  *  **No Disclosure to Third Party Companies for Marketing.**  As stated above, we will not disclose personal information that we have collected from Children to any third party company for the third party company’s own direct marketing purposes.
  *  **Disclosure to Other Third Parties Only With Consent.**  Beyond the disclosures described in this Privacy Policy, Socrative will not disclose your Personal Data to any other third party without a Teacher or School’s consent to do so.

#### Our Use of Cookies and Other Tracking Mechanisms

**Cookies.**  We use cookies to track information about a Child’s use of our Site, Apps, or Services. “Cookies” are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to a computer’s hard drive through a web browser for record-keeping purposes. We may use both session Cookies (which expire once a user closes a web browser) and persistent Cookies (which stay on a computer until a user deletes them). Some Cookies allow us to make it easier for a Child to navigate our Site and Services, while others are used to enable a faster log-in process or to allow us to track a Child’s activities, but only as those activities relate to a Child’s use of our Site and Service.

**Third-Party Analytics.**  We may also use third party analytics tools and technologies, such as Google Analytics, to track and analyze data from our Site, Apps, or Services. Google Analytics uses Cookies to collect information such as how often users visit the Site, what pages they visit, and what other sites they used prior to coming to the Site. We use the data collected by such third party analytics tools only to help us administer and improve the quality of our Site, Apps, and Services and to analyze Site and Apps usage. These third parties are not permitted to use the information collected on our behalf, except to help us conduct and improve our business. Google Analytics collects only the IP address assigned to a user on the date the user visits the Site, rather than a user’s name or other personally identifying information. Although Google Analytics plants a persistent Cookie on a user’s web browser to identify the user as a unique user the next time the user visits the Site, the Cookie cannot be used by anyone but Google. Google’s ability to use and share information collected by Google Analytics about a user’s visits to the Site is restricted by the Google Analytics Terms of Use and the Google Privacy Policy. For more information on Google’s privacy practices, please [click here](https://www.google.com/intl/en/analytics/learn/privacy.html). For information about how to opt out of Google Analytics, please [click here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

#### Third-Party Links

Teachers may provide Children with links to third-party educational and learning resources located on third party websites. Any access to and use of such linked websites is not governed by this COPPA Policy, but instead is governed by the privacy policies of those third-party websites. We are not responsible for the information practices of such third-party websites.

#### Your Rights to Review, Delete, and Control Our Use of Children’s Personal Information

Parents and Teachers have a right to review and correct the information we have collected about their Child(ren) and Students, respectively, and to delete it, and to tell us to update it or stop using it. To exercise these rights, you may contact us at [legal@socrative.com](mailto:legal@socrative.com). You will be required to authenticate yourself as the Child’s parent or Teacher to receive information about that Child. Please note that we cannot delete copies of information that a Child’s Teacher has already collected and/or copied, and copies of information that you have deleted may remain viewable in cached and archived pages of the Site or Apps for a period of time.

#### Additional Choices Regarding Children’s Personal Information

**Disabling Cookies.**  Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but if you prefer, you can edit your browser options to block them in the future. The Help portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your computer from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable cookies altogether. Visitors to our Site who disable cookies will be able to browse certain areas of the Site, but some features may not be available to you.

**Applications.**  You can stop all collection of information by the App(s) by uninstalling the App(s). You may use the standard uninstall processes as may be available as part of your mobile device or via the mobile application marketplace or network.

#### Changes to this COPPA Policy

This COPPA Policy is current as of the Last Updated date set forth above. We may change this COPPA Policy from time to time, so please be sure to check back periodically. If we make any changes to this COPPA Policy that materially affect our practices with regard to the personal information we have previously collected from a Child, we will provide you with notice in advance of such change becoming effective by emailing you at the address we have on file for you and by highlighting the change on our Site.

#### ADDENDUM – 1.1 SHOWBIE INC. EU PRIVACY SHIELD AND SWISS-U.S. PRIVACY SHIELD CERTIFICATION INFORMATION

**EU-US PRIVACY SHIELD AND SWISS-U.S. CERTIFICATIONS**  
The following information aligns Showbie US, Inc.’s (also doing business as Socrative) Statement with the specific points required by the Privacy Shield self-certification process, and ensures Socrative’s compliance with the EU-US Privacy Shield and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework.

**Compliance.**  Socrative complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of Personal Information transferred from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States. Socrative has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. If there is any conflict between the terms in this Privacy Policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>

**Complaints.**  In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, Socrative to resolve complaints about our collection or use of your Personal Information. EU and Swiss individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding our Privacy Shield Policy should first contact Socrative at [privacy@socrative.com.](mailto:privacy@socrative.com)

Socrative has further committed to cooperate with the panel established by the EU data protection authorities (DPAs) and the Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner (FDPIC) with regard to unresolved Privacy Shield complaints concerning data transferred from the EU and Switzerland. Please note that, under limited circumstances, a binding arbitration option may be available before a Privacy Shield panel. Socrative is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC).

**Organization Information**

Showbie Inc. (Also doing business as Socrative)  
#403, 10113 104 Street NW  
Edmonton, AB T5J 1A1 Canada
